Alright people!
And in this relentless heat,
...that was 'Radio Mamba International'.
A taste of The Black Mamba's new album,
debuting tonight
at Purgatory Itself: Babel.
Don't you dare miss it!
That's my husband...
People call him "El Boticario".
Now he's selecting the Shadows
he'll work with during the day.
Erato grew up in a traveling circus,
...and stopped talking
when she was seven years old.
Nobody knows why.
She likes to write sad love poems
on dirty mirrors in the bathrooms of bars.
She's the silent muse of this story.
Today's your lucky day...
Today, we will guide your visit
into our world.
Get a haircut!
That's Roma,
an old friend of Boticario's.
He shares a flat with Monet,
who's a poet...
...but sells drugs to pay for rent.
RAINS OVER BABEL
Darling...
When will you fix the pipes?
As you can see...
They don't get along too well.
Ay, oí! Darla!
Blessings, pastor!
God bless you.
Blessings and all!
Got a coin?
A coin for him? He's leaving already.
At 6 am, love!
...and with this weather!
That's my man, beauties, my boyfriend.
You'll end up as pale as he is, dear.
...From how hard he'll give it to me, ha!
Ay, oí! Hmm!
Alright. Back to practice.
Ay, no!
But if you think it's wrong
to serve the Lord...
Choose for yourselves
who you're going to serve.
As for my family and I...
...we will serve the Lord.
Amen!
Family is very important
before the eyes of God.
Amen!
That's why we have to work!
Understand that well...
Work!
To keep it united!
That's right!
...and to worship the Lord!
Amen!
Let's pray together
for our families this month...
So the Almighty Father may protect
and strengthen them.
Miguel...
You're upsetting the congregation.
You're welcome to talk to me...
But in private.
Magdalena...
My name is now Magdalena, pastor.
Please leave.
May my God bless you.
Boticario!
Have you seen Timbí?
No, Salai.
Is everything okay?
El Callegüeso has gone missing.
Wake up, man. It's late.
What a lazy bastard.
What's this?
I got it from...
You need to find El Callegüeso,
he's not answering my calls.
Yes, sir.
Come on! Get to work!
How was the shift?
They've been gambling all night.
Again?
What can be done?
La Flaca and her guests
can't be thrown out.
Pick one.
Careful, the devil's gonna eat you!
Pick one!
By the salamander's conch!
Now we're really up a creek.
Another five years, Flaca.
But first...
I need a drink.
Gonna drink every bottle of rum in Babel?
Leave some for the pirates!
Uma...
How's it going?
Bad.
I just lost fifteen years.
The table has been brought up.
The 43 boxes have arrived, and...
Darla asked us to let her
debut a new drag queen...
...Andria Luxury.
More faggots in this city?
Dad, you know all the clients they bring.
Yeah, yeah. Whatever.
If it goes wrong...
...she won't put her damn heels
in this bar again, you hear?
Look at that.
Check out that piece of ass.
She's fine, ain't she?
Go on, slap her ass.
What's wrong, Timbí?
She's a bum, a wench, a dirty thief...
She's worth nothing...
...but she's damn hot.
Go slap her.
No, dad.
Learn by example, fag.
Motherfucker.
What's wrong with you, wanker?
Borja!
No, you don't get it!
Let me be, I'm fine.
Is it bad?
It'll be fine.
Hm! If La Flaca thinks she won
the years you just bet...
She can take her at any moment.
Yes. And she'll have to go with her.
You have to get back in
and fix this, now.
Hey!
You!
Can you tell the bartender to open the
back door for me?
Hello, Flaquita.
Do you have today's list?
That's Dante, La Flaca's right-hand man.
Her debt collector.
He doesn't age
because he died twenty years ago.
And in that limbo he stayed,
waiting for his contract to end...
You know what date it is today?
Our contract ends today.
Thing is, he doesn't remember
what deal he made.
He lost his memory, and doesn't
remember who he was before he died.
Only that he was a soldier.
Do you have your amulet?
Bring it to Babel tonight.
And when El Callegüeso plays
"The Taste of Guayaba"... Puff!
...You hand it to me.
If you don't get it to me
before the song ends,
...you're mine another twenty years, love.
Now go.
As you wish, Flaquita.
Boticario...
The gypsy wants you
to open the back door for her.
El Callegüeso still isn't answering.
If this event goes wrong...
The Loan Sharks will skin me, you follow?
But if we smash it,
as everyone is expecting...
We'll pay all our debts.
You have to find him, Timbí...
...and make sure he arrives
to the concert in time.
Hey!
Don't you dare open the
back door for that motherfucking gypsy!
Chill, Salai,
I'm just going to take a shit.
Boticario... Come here, do me favor.
Where can Timbí look for El Callegüeso?
Serious business...
Bar Baco...
If he's not there,
maybe at My Petite Pony.
You heard that, shithead?
Find El Callegüeso before midnight.
Do you get what we're gambling here?
If you don't make it in time...
They'll kill you.
And you too, kid.
Go now.
El Callegüeso...
Salsa singer, sax player, and dealer of
memories of the future.
Good morning.
He's 150 years old, but looks 43...
Time doesn't pass for him
since he won a bet against La Flaca.
He's The Black Mamba's singer,
always dressed in white...
...with a straw hat.
He's always late to his gigs...
But his band is a powerhouse of,
check this out...
Pure salsa.
And this story revolves
around his concert.
I know I'll get kicked out...
Give me two minutes!
I just need to clarify something
with La Flaca!
It's life or death!
Flaca! Flaca!
So...
How'd it go?
To surrender ourselves, pray for luck...
...or may death bless us.
Claudio Monet is one of the
people I'm meant to guard.
But today is the last day we'll meet.
Today is a special day,
because today Monet will die....
...but he doesn't know that yet.
She warns you.
"A warned soldier doesn't die in war"
Trafficked by El Callegüeso
from the Floating Islands of Bangladesh.
Cassiopea?
Calliope?
Talk to me, muses.
Who goes first?
No, love...
I don't do that stuff.
Chicken.
Are you leaving me alone with this one?
There is innocence behind sin.
Without original innocence,
there would be no original sin.
I won't do it either, love.
She's warned you.
See you at The Black Mamba's concert?
Till then.
"A warned soldier doesn't die in war"
Doña Elba?
Were you sleeping?
Must be asfixia during sleep...
I didn't even feel it.
But I've seen it coming
since my husband died.
Oh, boy.
I quit 30 years ago
because "it would kill me"...
Whatever.
My children and grandchildren
never visit...
If they take too long, I'll become one
of those horror stories...
...where the cat eats the body.
Here...
Put it here.
Drink some of this, ma'am.
Sweetheart...
How did you end up
collecting debts for La Flaca?
Do you have your amulet?
Bye, Fru Fru.
Don't you dare eat me, you hear?
Safe travels, Doña Elba.
We like that girl, don't we Jacob?
Jacob?
Well, I don't like her mother.
Mariana, the carpenter's wife,
says the girl's father is a drunk.
He doesn't answer for her
nor for the girl.
And people say
she wants to be an actress...
An actress!
When have you seen an actress
be a pastor's wife?
The girl is still young.
We can make her change her mind
before she marries Jacob, right?
In any case,
that's the least of our problems.
The person I really need to talk to
is Miguel.
Showing up like that to the sermon?
...with that dress, those heels,
and a face full of makeup!
My God...
It makes sense...
No wonder Fernando and his wife
haven't returned to the sermon.
Did you like your food, Jacob?
"God does not show favoritism"
In God's eyes, we are all equal.
Pardon?
Peter. Verse 34 to 35.
What are you suggesting, Jacob?
That I have to accept that Miguel,
whom I've known since his childhood,
Whom I've seen grow up,
whose parents I know,
walks the streets, selling himself?
Tell me!
That I should not advise him,
lead him to the Lord?
She's not a man dressed as a woman, dad...
...She is a woman.
God made him a man...
...and a man he'll die before God's eyes.
Before His eyes, or yours?
More mashed potatoes?
No, I'm good.
Mom!
I need to change, I'm late for the match.
You need energy for the match.
Proverbs 6:20...
"Keep thy father's commandment...
...and forsake not the law of thy mother."
Excuse me.
What can I get you?
What have you got there?
The youngest bottle is 30 years old.
Do you see that gypsy?
Gypsy!
When did we open this bar?
1789.
Do you see that boat over there?
We all arrived in it.
It's wrinkled and shrunk...
...but it proves us gypsies
don't grow old.
What's wrong?
Someone I care about is dying.
Any others would say they're sorry, but...
Boys!
Who here is dying?
Young lady...
We're all dying.
Life is but a race against the grave.
Hey, gypsy, sing to us.
Let's go.
Blind are the Gods,
Blind is Fortune,
Blind are men,
without light and the moon.
Blind are the Gods,
Blind is Fortune,
Blind are men,
without light and the moon.
Good evening, Don Fabio...
Has El Callegüeso been around?
No, it's been days since I've seen him.
Thank you.
Are you on foot?
What do you want?
To help you find El Callegüeso.
Rumor has it he's at "My Petite Pony".
They ask for a password at the entrance...
It's a labyrinth,
hard to navigate if you don't know it.
Lucky for you...
...You have me.
In exchange for what?
Get me back into your bar and
tell your guards to leave me alone.
Don't you have
anything else to do in life?
Besides betting against La Flaca?
A job? A family?
How long have you been gambling?
Four months and fifteen days, baby.
Yo, who said that?
You can hear her?
What a pretty boy!
My pleasure, handsome.
Same?
What is that?
Sloppy!
You're slouching!
Stand correctly!
Have you learned nothing this whole time?
Let's start from the top!
Ready?
Lift me up!
Down, close to the mirror!
- Late!
- Sorry.
There is no room here
to say sorry... Nor to be late.
Andria, Queens are never late.
We are waiting for you, Andria.
Sorry, mother, I'm coming.
One more time! From the top.
What the hell was that?
Foul! Tacky! Ungraceful!
Head up, shoulders down.
The way we've rehearsed all this time.
Or have we wasted our time?
We are going to do it...
...and we are going to do it right.
Up!
And prep the ending!
You see?
How easy it is to be you?
Royal.
Going from the top!
I get it.
I'm still tripping on peyote.
I overdid it.
Milk... I need milk.
Fuck, I don't have milk.
Afternoon.
Is this Claudio Monet's house?
Overdose.
Bad luck, papi.
The judges down there won't like this.
Overdoses count as suicides.
What?
Uy, no... I'm too young to die.
Do you have your amulet?
What amulet?
Check your pockets.
What's this?
That's your Shadow.
It stays here with me
in the material world, and you...
You go through there.
Don't make this harder than it has to be.
- What's your name?
- Dante.
Dante...
Just say it...
How do I get back into my body?
Nothing, papi.
When it's your
time... it's your time.
Has nobody ever given you a second chance?
There's a way...
but I don't recommend it.
Look...
You have to make a deal with La Flaca
before your body decomposes.
Make a deal or seduce her.
It didn't go well for me...
How so?
Are you dead too?
I'm in a strange limbo,
Today my contract ends,
so I die completely.
So...
Tell me about her.
Don't you know La Flaca?
No...
This whole city revolves around her...
...although most don't understand
who she is.
She's the Death of this city.
So what?
Where do I find her?
She won't miss The Black Mamba's Concert.
Hello darlings...
- Looking for service?
- Timbí...
This is The Pythia.
We're looking for El Callegüeso.
What's in it for me?
No, papi...
He hasn't shown his face around here.
Where can I write?
Come in next time...
...we don't bite.
Come here.
This address doesn't exist.
"Dead-End Street 123"
Something smells fishy.
Rosa?
Honey, I'm gonna ask for something
you ain't gonna like.
Shit.
The things I do for that gypsy.
Sara Houston is not expecting
what's coming.
You are the golden touch of tonight.
She'll be divine.
Today you're born again.
Can I use the bathroom?
Are you okay?
Jacob?
Andria!
Are you okay?
The keys!
Where are the keys?
Which keys?
The bathroom keys!
Where are they?
Come on, search for them!
I'm damned.
Everything will be fine.
Don't let me burn in hell, Lord.
Don't say that, Andria.
Do you still want to do the show?
Calm down, kid.
We'll find him.
Then I'll take you back to that
gem of a father you have.
Look...
Salai isn't the best guy...
but he's the only thing I've got.
My mom left us when I was five,
and it's been hard for him...
...to raise me on his own.
Your mom...
Did you ever forgive her?
How do you hold a grudge against a ghost?
What would you do without me, huh?
Rosa...
...do your thing, baby.
Nap time, baby.
Lights out!
What floor, señores?
Room -777.
The Thanatos.
Underworld...
-6.
Thanatos... -7.
How was the soccer match?
Good, dad.
- Blessings, mom.
- God bless you, my love.
Don't worry about it,
go watch TV with your dad.
No worries, mom....
I'll help you.
Jacob, don't be angry at your father.
Look, all fingers point at him...
...at us.
Who else will set example
at the congregation?
We have to think in a certain way,
speak in a certain way...
I know, mom.
I know.
Mom, would you pass me the bread please?
Yes, love.
What a fool.
Don't talk to yourself like that, mom.
Throw some salt over your shoulder.
Yes...
You're such a romantic comedy,
and I... an existential drama.
Hey there, little bird.
That's La Flaca, right there...
If you can't make it...
I'll catch you later.
Looking for something?
Weren't you upstairs?
Please!
The receptionist is my brother, Delos.
I am Delfos.
How odd...
I didn't get a notice clients were comin'.
My wife and I...
...are looking for a room
for our anniversary.
Mrs. Deep Purple...
You change husbands
like you change your knickers.
Hun, you know I don't wear knickers.
We're looking...
...for a 7-7-8.
Occupied.
Of the sevens I have the 772 and 773 left.
That's the one you used
with the owner of the bar,
Mister Sa...
Sa...
The Pythia says Thanatos Agents
are the most discreet,
and if she knows you squealed...
She won't like it.
Two lovers lost in the Artic...
Drama...
Passion...
But also...
this room...
...has the best air conditioning.
Whattaya say?
Son, will you be long?
No, I'm almost done.
Jacob!
Yes, mom, I'll be right out.
Dad?
I'm sorry.
God bless you, my son.
Yes?
Jacob, can we talk?
Let's talk tomorrow, mom,
I'm going to bed.
Remember we love you a lot...
I love you guys a lot too...
Good night.
Jacob?
Come on, Flaquita...
It was a mistake.
...can't I just go back to my body?
I already told you no...
Whose fault is it you overdosed?
Why do you want to stay?
Fame? Fortune?
You want history to remember you?
Would that make you happy?
No.
Then you're afraid of death...
...That's it.
Do you believe in hell?
Yes, hell exists.
And God?
God died in a Shakespearean tragedy,
dressed as a woman...
...it was Shakespeare's revenge.
But Shakespeare also died...
and he's in hell,
it was God's revenge.
Where's my other glove?
Mother, can you help me?
Good evening, ladies.
Good evening.
Sara Houston goes on in half an hour.
You follow when she's done.
I want to ask for a favor...
with all due respect.
Please don't make fools of yourselves.
Hello?
"Please don't make fools of yourselves."
Pathetic.
Slimy.
What's Sara Houston gonna do?
Salsa, what else?
I'm so bored of her.
You read her, girl!
Hello.
Old man Salai,
do me a favor...
...tell the boy at the bar
that our bill is on the house.
Boss.
Give them whatever they want.
Hey, has my son arrived yet?
No, Salai.
And El Callegüeso?
Haven't seen him.
Where the fuck are they?
1350 BC.
She is a princess...
...and he's a palace guard.
And if they get caught...
...both will die.
It's $80 for twelve hours
and $25 for four.
Whattaya say?
We have sexy period costumes.
Mother, I left my fan
in the dressing room.
Sorry.
I know you.
You're the pastor's son.
Why are you dressed like that?
He's gonna kill him.
Damn! What a beating you gave those two.
Watch the door while I get him out.
Why is it so important
to get into the bar?
Just to gamble with La Flaca?
What are you hiding?
Hey, handsome.
If she asks, I didn't tell you.
Winning against La Flaca
is the only way...
to save her daughter...
...who is dying.
Don't they call you The Aspirin?
No, honey...
...Deep Purple.
Why are you helping me, Miss Purple?
You're late to your gig.
Which one is today?
Babel.
Go get her.
Why me, love?
No!
...Darla!
Let's go, Andria.
I'm not coming out.
Come on, drop the act.
Andria, this always happens at first...
...once you go on stage,
the nerves will stop.
It's normal!
I can't do this to my parents.
Forgive me, Darla, I wasted your time...
Wake up, Jacob.
One day, you'll get tired of pretending.
Leave her!
Let's go!
Honey, I get you.
You?
You don't get anything.
My father was an Imam.
By five, he had me reciting
entire paragraphs of the Qur'an.
He always gave me
everything I asked for...
...and I adored him.
When I was 15, he found me in my
mother's closet, dressed as a woman...
He threw himself on top of me,
and began to suffocate me...
...he was going to kill me.
My mother found us
and screamed for my brother...
...he saved my life.
He told me to run,
I ran...
...and I ran,
...and never looked back.
I had to dance in brothels to survive.
Mother Darla found me one day,
and brought me into the academy.
I understand more than you know.
Sometimes, the best thing
is to jump into the void,
and let what has to burn... burn.
I'll be waiting for you...
...or not.
Excuse me...
Where's your body?
My body?
3:08 AM.
Oops, I'm a little early.
I'll be back in a few minutes.
Dante...
I love you!
Let me say goodbye to him.
Please.
Gian?
It's time, Alimaña
El Callegüeso isn't going to show.
It can't be.
I buried you myself.
Gian, I'm here.
It's real.
Wow, that's a lot.
Let's split.
Run!
Cerberus, don't let them escape!
On it, boss. I'll let the beasts out.
Oh, boy.
You're not leaving
till you've paid your debt.
Look, calm down...
You're my only girl, I swear on my wife!
Pay up!
Don't worry, boss, I'll get him.
You gotta pay up!
Well this is just great.
Nobody panic.
Cerberus is my kung-fu teacher.
Ain't that right, master?
- Bullshit. Business is business.
- For real?
Did you forget I saved you from
the Pandebono Mafia in '74?
Did you forget or what?
Wake up! Wake up!
Motherfucker...
Callegüeso!
You're not leaving till
you've paid! Pay me!
I'll make you that red scorpion soup
you like for hangovers!
I'll see you at home, okay?
Where are my glasses, Rosa?
My glasses!
Quick!
Where's Rosa?
I won't leave without her!
Step on it, bitch!
Let's go!
My child.
They say Guardian Angels
shouldn't have favorites.
And if someone asks...
I never told you this, you hear?
God does not hate anyone.
It is men,
imperfect, proud...
Who under the flag of the divine,
condemn those like you...
to feel superior.
It was you...
...who chose to burn
for the way you think.
This is for all my people!
Let them speak ill of me,
They don't get it
I'm getting better and better.
They want to stop me,
but I won't let them!
Keep the chorus playing,
I've been blessed by the heavens!
Gold hangs from my neck,
I'm colder than ice
Keep the chorus playing,
I've been blessed by the heavens!
Hey, Borja.
- You can't go in.
- Let me in!
It's cool, she's with me.
Let's go, come on.
Mamba! Mamba!
Dante! Dante!
Saved by the saxophone.
We are The Black Mamba!
We are Embera and Tolteca!
We are a free people!
We are Yoruba and Bantú
From Latin America!
French, Portuguese...
We are who we are!
We're the mix of thousands!
We are The Black Mamba!
We are Muisca. We are Wayúu.
We are a Free People!
We are Lucumí drums!
From Latin America!
The blend of English and Spanish!
Now it's for real... We're
seeing The Black Mamba!
We are who we are!
Walking forward! Ay!
Moving forward,
Changing things,
The things that don't work anymore!
We are who we are!
We're the mix of thousands!
We're The Black Mamba!
We are Embera and Tolteca!
We are a free people!
We are Yoruba and Bantú
From Latin America!
We are Lucumí drums!
We are many, walking forward!
We are who we are
And we're moving on now! Ay!
What's your woman like?
Sweet,
beautiful.
Her teeth have a gap in the middle...
When she laughs, my whole world spins.
And when she dances...
I'm happy for you...
...Salai.
To see that you're happy.
Well, not exactly.
She left me.
But I know she loves me,
I know she loves me and she'll come back.
Just like you...
No?
Dad...
Is everything okay?
Your son?
Thanks for helping
me with the loan sharks, man.
I just met him.
Let me buy you a drink.
You just met me?!
You just met me!
It's all good, son, all good.
I waited twenty years
to say goodbye to you...
...and you just met me?
What the hell.
What the hell!
You okay?
Yes.
What was it you said to me this morning?
"More faggots in this city?"
Flaca!
I spent 20 years not knowing
what the name Gian Salai meant,
just to have this shit happen?
What's wrong, baby?
I don't force anyone
to make deals with me.
I was doing you a favor, remember?
Go back to hell.
Where do you think we are?
I never left.
Come here.
Remember, when
"The Taste of Guayaba' plays,
I'm expecting your shadow.
Otherwise...
You'll be mine
for another twenty years, love.
Hey, Flaquita...
If this is hell, then who is...
The one you least expect, Monet.
I buried him with my bare hands.
I thought it was divine punishment...
...for being a faggot.
All I had left was that necklace...
...with his name on it.
What then?
I changed...
180 degrees, I...
I went to a reformatory
to cure homosexuality...
...and I got a mask.
Afterwards, I couldn't get it off.
It hurt too much.
What a burden to carry.
But then I met your mom...
...and I fell in love.
I fell for real.
She was so beautiful.
So androgynous.
Her personality resembled his, but...
...she was a woman.
Is that why she left?
She found out?
No, no.
I don't believe so.
Rather, it was the mask.
It ended up sabotaging my life.
Thank you, son.
Why, dad?
For bringing El Callegüeso?
You know something, Boticario?
We have to let the Gods decide
what's best for us.
They know us more than we know ourselves.
If we're going to ask for something...
Let us ask for a strong spirit...
One that's not afraid of death.
That's the song.
I gotta go close the deal with La Flaca.
Goodbye, Boticario.
Have a nice life.
Dante.
Monet's body has not decomposed yet.
And yours?
Hey, Flaquita...
I have a deal for you.
Uh huh. What's in it for me?
What's the elixir of your life?
An empty glass.
An empty glass?
To bet against La Flaca.
100 years...
...for my daughter.
If I win, I'll take her tonight.
Two ones.
Two twos.
Two six.
Three sixes.
My life.
One more game.
My life for my daughter's.
Four sixes.
Five sixes.
Thank you.
Easy, girl.
You'll help me settle a debt as payback.
Boticario!
Have you seen Uma?
No!
You okay?
Did she wake up?
Put her on the phone.
Put her on the phone, Luciano...
Hello?
How do you feel?
Why aren't you here?
Are you coming back?
Yes.
I'm coming...
I'm coming to see you.
I'm finally coming home.
I love you.
It's okay, honey, it's okay.
So... now what?
Let's split?
Mmm... Look at that!
Hi, love.
Ready to go?
The great majority of people...
...never discover
the meaning of their own lives.
Life is more than protecting identities...
What is the meaning of this, gentlemen?
Gentlemen!
You are disturbing my congregation.
I'm asking you to leave!
Silence!
Jacob?
Anyways,
Monet, the poet,
fell in love with Death.
...and stayed with Her.
And Dante...
the broken-hearted soldier,
got his second chance.
After all,
Why waste a perfectly fresh body?
What's the elixir of your life?
And with a whiz and a bang,
this story is told, just like that!